(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T21:39:03.920458",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
3、2、1！
3, 2, 1!
わんつーで参拝！
One, two, shrine visit!
みこみこみこ！
Miko-miko-miko!
いえーい！
Yay!
みんな明けましておめでとうございます！今年もエリートで頑張っていくぞー！
Happy New Year, everyone! I'll do my best as an elite this year too!
電脳世界からやってきた ウザカワ系バーチャル巫女アイドル！
A cutesy-annoying virtual shrine maiden idol from cyberspace!
ついに来たよ！お待たせ！
Finally here! Thanks for waiting!
待ちに待ったうへへへ♪
I've been waiting for this, uhehehe♪
電脳世界からやってきた
Coming straight from cyberspace,
ウザカワ系バーチャル巫女アイドル！
a cutesy-annoying virtual shrine maiden idol!
わたしはそうエリート！
I am so elite!
なんていったってエリート！
No matter what, I'm elite!
エリート巫女？ エリートアイドル？
Elite shrine maiden? Elite idol?
そんなの両方に決まってるじゃん！
It's obviously both of those!
いじわるも泣き虫も神サマも！
Teasers, crybabies, and even gods!
崇め奉れたら巫女パワーで幸せ分けてあげてもいいんだよ？
If you worship me, I can share my shrine maiden power with you!
みこちゃんはー？ エリートです！
What is Miko-chan? She's elite!
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃ・うーにゃー・にゃー！
Miko-miko-miko, honyahonya, unya, nya!
さくら・くるくる・さくらみこ！ みこみこみこで むにゃむにゃ・すやすや……ぐー！
Sakura, revolving, Sakura Miko! Miko-miko-miko, munyamunya, sleepy... zzz!
明日から本気だす！（エリートですから！）
I'll get serious starting tomorrow! (Because I'm elite!)
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃ・うーにゃー・にゃー！ 金時はほにゃほにゃ・かぷっ……幸せの太鼓
Miko-miko-miko, honyahonya, unya, nya! Kintoki is honyahonya, nom... Drums of happiness,
ポンポコリン リンリン！ みんな笑顔になあれ！
ponpokorin linlin! May everyone have a smile on their face!
わんつーで参拝！ みこみこみこ！ いえーい！
One, two, shrine visit! Miko-miko-miko! Yay!
ちょっとだけ休憩タイム
Just a little break time,
マイペースだけど許してね！ 実はこれも修行のうちです
but please forgive my pace! Actually, this is part of my training too.
そんなわけはなくなくない……あっバレたーっ！
There's no way that's... Ah, I got caught!
わたしはそうエリート！
I am so elite!
嘘じゃないよ！エリート！
I'm not lying! Elite!
エリート巫女？ エリートアイドル？
Elite shrine maiden? Elite idol?
今日もがんばって粋ましょう！
Let's keep doing our best today too!
ココロ模様 曇り空 雨の日も 問題ない！
Cloud days and rainy days? No problem!
巫女パワーで それ 晴れ晴れエトセトラ 騒いじゃおうよ！
With shrine maiden power, let's cause a cheerful, sunny uproar!
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃ・うーにゃー・にゃー！ さくら・くるくる・さくらみこ！
Miko-miko-miko, honyahonya, unya, nya! Sakura, revolving, Sakura Miko!
みこみこみこで むにゃむにゃ・もぐもぐ…… たい焼きでたい焼き（ピーマンは no thank you！）
Miko-miko-miko, munyamunya, mogumogum... Taiyaki, taiyaki (bell peppers are no thank you!)
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃ・うーにゃー・にゃー！ カミサマもほにゃほにゃ・かぷっ……
Miko-miko-miko, honyahonya, unya, nya! Even the gods, honyahonya, nom...
元気の呪文 巫女巫女舞舞舞！ みんな笑顔になあれ！
Spell of vitality, shrine maiden dance, dance, dance! May everyone have a smile on their face!
what time is it now ?
What time is it now?
one-one-three-five!
say in japanese!
（い・い・み・こ！）
(I-i-mi-ko!)
what time is it now ?
What time is it now?
one-one-three-five!
say in japanese!
（い・い・み・こ！）
(I-i-mi-ko!)
はー1人でいると考えていこうじゃな
When I'm all alone, I start overthinking—
（どうしたの？）
(What's wrong?)
自信と不安でサンドイッチ
Sandwiched between confidence and anxiety,
分かかんなくなっちゃった
I lost track of everything.
みこかわいい？
Is Miko cute?
（超かわいい！）
(Super cute!)
間違ってないのだ！君がいる
I'm not wrong! Having you here—
（みこちはエリート！）
(Miko-chi is elite!)
だよにゃー！
That's right, nya!
（ほんとにエリート！？）
(Really elite!?)
でゃまれ！
Shut up!
（みこ、俺恥ずかしいよ…）
(Miko, I'm so embarrassed...)
言って好きなくせににゃ～！
Saying you like me anyway, nya~♪
毎分毎秒ドッジボール
Playing dodgeball every minute and second,
あっちゅういね楽しいね
It flies by so fast, so much fun!
本気で想い合ってそのくせ
Sincerely caring for each other,
バカばっか言い合って好き勝手やってんね
Yet we just trade silly banter and do as we please.
でも今日ぐらいは
But at least for today,
ちゃんと聞いててね？
Please listen closely, okay?
控え目に言って神伝えたい愛
To put it modestly, my love is divine.
朝も夜も胸いっぱいさ
My heart is full, morning and night.
くらくらしちゃってたまんないの
I'm getting dizzy, I can't take it!
純度100%で大好きだ！
I love you with 100% purity!
チュッてゲッツてチャージング
Kiss, get, charging—
全世界共通
Universal across the world,
チュッてゲッツてチャージング
Kiss, get, charging,
ラブアンドピース
Love and peace!
きっとお似合いだよユーアンドミー
We're surely a match, you and me,
このまま二人で……なんてねー！
The two of us like this... just kidding!
11:35!
say in japanese!
1135!
what time is it now ?
What time is it now?
1135!
say in japanese!
今宵もみこの良いところ
Tonight's another great thing about Miko—
（全ロス！全ロス！）
(Total loss! Total loss!)
なんでハプニングばかなの～！？
Why is it always just mishaps?!
（ポンコツ！ポンコツ！）
(Useless! Useless!)
オイ今何時だっ！ライン越えてんぞ！
Hey, what time is it?! You're crossing the line!
まーででも…遊んでくれてありがとね？
Well, still... thanks for playing with me, okay?
想像以上の熱量が背中を押してくれる
Passion beyond imagination pushes my back,
1人じゃないんだね一緒に創ろうね
I'm not alone, let's create it together!
みんなのパラダイスでにゃっはろー！
Nyahallo to everyone's paradise!
君にも届けたい他にはないアミューズメント
I want to reach you too with a unique amusement,
「いいみこ」って届けて毎日
Delivering "Good Miko" everyday.
目を合わせたら笑ってくれる
When our eyes meet, you smile back—
当たり前のような奇跡
A miracle that feels so ordinary.
もらってばかりじゃいらんない
I can't just keep receiving,
今ここで恩返し
I'll repay you right here and now.
ずっと見ていてね？
Keep watching me forever, okay?
控え目に言って神伝えたい愛
To put it modestly, my love is divine.
朝も夜も胸いっぱいさ
My heart is full, morning and night.
くらくらしちゃってたまんないの
I'm getting dizzy, I can't take it!
純度100%で大好きだ！
I love you with 100% purity!
チュッてゲッツてチャージング
Kiss, get, charging—
全世界共通
Universal across the world,
チュッてゲッツてチャージング
Kiss, get, charging,
ラブアンドピース
Love and peace!
きっとお似合いだよユーアンドミー
We're surely a match, you and me,
飽きるほど一杯隣で歌うよ
I'll sing right next to you until we're sick of it.
このまま二人で………なんてねー！
The two of us like this......... just kidding!
11:35!
say in japanese!
はーいということで、皆さん、新年明けまして、おめでとうございます！
Hii! So everyone, Happy New Year!
2023年の「みこも」飛ばしていくぞ！うおー！うおー！
We're gonna dash through Miko-mo in 2023! Woo! Woo!
はい、ということで、え、本日は新年1月2日ということでね、まあ
Yes, so, um, today is January 2nd of the New Year, so, you know,
お正月っぽいことをね、色々していきます。
we'll be doing various New Year-ish things.
ということで、まあ、お正月一緒にもね、アニメもありますので、最後まで皆さん、ぜひぜひ見てくださいね！
So, um, since there's also a New Year anime together, everyone please be sure to watch until the very end!
最後にね、もう重大な告知もあるかもや、あります！よろしくね！それでは、
Lastly, there might even be a major announcement—there is! Please look forward to it! Now then—
お、次のコーナー、ちょっと早速ゲストがいらっしゃるので行ってきまーす！はーい！はーい！
Oh, for the next corner, since some guests have already arrived, I'm heading over! Hii! Hii!
新年明けまして、おめでとうございます！
Happy New Year!
ということでね、ゲストをお呼びしております。
So, we've invited some guests.
じゃあ皆さんね、あの1人ずつ自己紹介と一緒に抱負もね、今年の抱負も言ってもらえればなと、思います。やった！
Now everyone, I'd like each of you to introduce yourselves along with your New Year's resolutions for this year. Yay!
はーい、皆さん！あきもき1つにしろかみです！
Hi everyone! Shirakami Fubuki, dedicated to my oshigoto and passions!
今年の一年の抱負は色々あるんですけども、まあ、そうですね、まあガシャの回し過ぎをしないのと、まあまあすぐ駆け込みをしないってことですかね、ねえ皆さんね。
As for my resolution for this year, there are various things, but well, yeah, not spinning gacha too much, and not rushing into things at the last minute, right everyone?
それだけみこさんがいるとやっぱやりがちなんですよね。現ピラになりますからね。あい、じゃあ続いて、あの今日やりすぎないようにと、はい。
When Miko-san is around, you tend to end up doing that. You become a pyramid. Alright, next, and trying not to overdo it today, yes.
ポポポポ！来ましたおめでとうございます！
Popopo! It's here, Happy New Year!
ポポは、えっと、健康にも気をつけながら、うーん、何だっけ？みんなと今年遊びたいな、いっぱいもっと。
Popo will, um, while taking care of my health, um, what was it? I want to play a lot more with everyone this year.
色んな書き起こしした、おみせを漢字、漢字して、え？え？お店の予約とっとととっておけばいい。おお、そうそう、敷地の畳を見る。
I want to make lots of reservations and see the kotatsu tatami!
はい、え、星川のことから現れたさの、芸術家、あけおめVTuberの星街すいせいでーす。
Yes, um, Hoshimachi Suisei here, artist and New Year VTuber!
私の抱負ですか？はい、抱負ですね。
My resolution? Yes, my resolution.
ええっと、まあ、1月にまずアルバムとライブがね、ありますので、まずはそこを頑張るということで、はい。そこを乗り越えたら、その時はその時で。はい。
Um, well, in January we first have an album and a live show coming up, so first of all, I'll do my best there, yes. Once I get through that, we'll deal with whatever comes then. Yes.
敷き込みとかせんもかさならないように、楽しくてね、今年もビジネス、よろしくお願いいたします！はい、新年からね、早速呼ばれてしまいました、ビジネスですけれども。
Trying not to overlap with rush work, having fun, business as usual this year too, please treat me well! Yes, getting called right from the start of the New Year, though it's business.
え、みこちゃん？えっと、まあ、あるんですけど、今回はね、ちょっと気合を入れたのかな？おっ、
Um, Miko-chan? Um, well, there is one, but this time, did I put in extra effort? Oh—
っていう感じしてちょっとまあ、豆腐をね、掲げに、なんと…
With that kind of vibe, like, holding up tofu, of all things...
ロケを！ロケ！
location filming! Location!
みこがロケに行ってきたんだよ。
Miko went on location!
え？どこへ？
Eh? Where to?
まあ、それはVTR見てもらって…
Well, you'll see in the VTR...
みんなにちょっとVTR見てもらおうかなって。今日は飲み物とか飲みながらそういうのやる感じ？
I want everyone to watch the VTR. Are we doing this while drinking beverages or something?
まあ飲み物ではないんですけど、用意したものがね。
Well, not drinks per se, but we prepared something.
こちらどうぞ！
Here you go!
え！？どこ行って来たの！？
Eh?! Where did you go?!
なんかロケっぽいお客さんが、こう…
It feels like an on-location guest is like...
同期じゃん！大人のボタンの…
You're classmates! The adult button...
え、これ何なんすか？大人のボタンなの？
Eh, what is this? Is it an adult button?
これは、あの、押してみてくださ…え？ちょっと待って、字幕と…
This is, um, please press it... Eh? Wait a minute, subtitles and...
字幕ちょっと待って！あ、V止めて！
Wait for subtitles! Ah, stop the VTR!
え、このボタンを使ってじゃあVTRを見るということですか？そうVTRを見て…
Eh, does that mean we use this button to watch the VTR? Yes, watch the VTR...
ちょっと待って！あの、突っ込んでいただ…あ、もう突っ込んでいただいたら…
Wait a minute! Um, if you could poke fun at it... Ah, once you poke fun at it...
なるほど！
I see!
ですよね。
Exactly.
ちょっと待て！
Hold on!
じゃあ行きますか？VTR。
Shall we go then? The VTR.
そっち？そうそうそっち。
That way? Yeah, yeah, that way.
それではじゃあ行きますか！はい！
Then let's go! Yes!
それでは早速、VTRどうぞー！
Now then, without further ado, here's the VTR!
（スタッフ）おはようございます。
(Staff) Good morning.
おはようございます。
Good morning.
いや～早いですね。
Man~ It's early.
朝4時に何をしてるんだよ！
What are we doing at 4 AM?!
いやいやいや、だってびっくりしたでしょ、ロケはさあれは。しかも最初からモザイク半端ないわけだし。
No no no, I mean you were surprised by the location shoot, right? Plus there's so much mosaic right from the start.
いやちょっと見ていただいてほら見てほら。まあ、モザイクは、そう、半端ないですね。
Well, take a look, see, look. Well, the mosaic is, yeah, pretty intense.
いや待ってそれはさ、当たり前だよね、ちょっと窓のところりがね、モザイクかかってる…それが心配では、じゃあ、待って！
Wait, that's obvious, right? Around the window has mosaic... if you're worried about that, then, wait!
だまれ！
Shut up!
いやその後のなんか、何ですかあの美子さんの座りわ…ちょっと進めてください。進めてください。
And what about after that, what is Miko's sitting pose... Please advance it. Please advance it.
（スタッフ）おはようございます。
(Staff) Good morning.
おはようございます。
Good morning.
いや～早いですね。
Man~ It's early.
これ、どこ向かうんでしたっけ？
Where were we heading again?
（スタッフ）まずは清めないといけないので、禊に向かいます。
(Staff) First we need to purify, so we're heading for ritual purification.
禊ぐことなんてね、こう、ないんですけどね。
We don't really do things like purification, though.
（スタッフ）あるでしょ～、ないでしょ～
(Staff) Of course there are~ No there aren't~
はいじゃあ、ま、先ほどまで配信やってたんでね。
Alright then, well, I was streaming just until a moment ago.
このまま寝て、朝起きたら、きっと、到着してるのかなって思うのでね。
If I just sleep like this and wake up in the morning, I figured we'd probably have arrived by then.
（スタッフ）今日はハードな1日になるので、今はゆっくり休んでください。
(Staff) Today is going to be a hard day, so please rest well for now.
がんばります。おやすみこ～
I'll do my best. Goodnight-miko~
ちょっと見てもらったらわかるんだけどさ、パンツ穿いてない。あの、あたしが、あ、違うかった。
If you watch it, you'll see, I'm not wearing panties. Um, I was, ah, no that's wrong.
あのね、揺れを最でんするために、ちょっとね、あの足をね、あの揺らしてみたら、なんか貧乏ゆすりみたいになって、ちょっとすごくタイツ悪くなっちゃったなと思って。
You know, to minimize the shaking, when I shook my leg a bit, it looked like restless legs, and I thought my tights looked really bad.
こういう車はね、もう揺れないからね、こう、こういう。
Cars like this don't shake anymore, like this, like this.
なんで自分でこうやってやるんだよ！
Why are you doing that yourself!
あ、じゃあ進めてもらって、はい、はい。
Ah, then please advance it, yes, yes.
結構どうでもいい話、どうでもいい話。
Pretty much a pointless story, pointless story.
え、破ってる、え、破って…
Eh, tearing it, eh, tearing...
寝れなさそう。寝たらいびきするからな。
Looks like I can't sleep. If I sleep I'll snore.
いびきするの？
You snore?
車に揺られること約3時間。
Shaken in a car for about 3 hours.
まずは禊へ。
First, to purification.
おい！おっそそう！
Hey! So late!
ちょっと待ってください！
Please wait a moment!
ナレーションが俺やんけ！
The narration is me!
本当だ！
True!
ナレーション！
Narration!
そのころ…え？ちょっと待って、あ、あの、私の方が田所あずさとの親密度高いんですけど！
Back then... Eh? Wait a minute, ah, um, my intimacy with Azusa Tadokoro is higher!
そうなんだよ！ね、ナレーション！
That's right! Right, narration!
超有名人気の田所あずささんをね。
The super famous and popular Azusa Tadokoro-san.
おおー！
Oooh!
いやー！おねがいする前に、あたしのコラボの前に！
Nooo! Before asking, before my collaboration!
その、ま、先仕込っていうね、段取りやってるんですけどね。さんざんピンチヒッターやったんだよ。
They're doing this preparation setup. I did pinch-hitting so much.
そうだね、4週私たちが寝てる間にピンチヒッターやってくれて。
That's right, she did pinch-hitting for 4 weeks while we slept.
もう仲良くも何ちゃいやね！
We're not even that close anymore!
おい、浮気ですよ、田所あずさ…
Hey, it's cheating, Azusa Tadokoro...
車に揺られること約3時間。
Shaken in a car for about 3 hours.
恐怖を祈願する前に、禊ぎへ向かう。
Before praying for fear, heading for purification.
やってできたのはこちら、茨城県大子町「月待の滝」。
What we arrived at here is "Tsukimachi Falls" in Daigo Town, Ibaraki Prefecture.
禊ぐことなんてないんだけど、滝に打たれたら出てくるかもしれない。
We don't really do purification, but if you get hit by the waterfall, something might come out.
とのことです。禊の一種 滝行に挑む。
That's what they say. Taking on waterfall training, a form of purification.
気温6℃。
Temperature 6°C.
みこさん！
Miko-san!
なんですか？
What is it?
美少年になっちゃってきたんですか？
Have you become a bishounen?
ね、滝に打たれたこと、だって滝に打たれるってさ
Hey, have you ever been hit by a waterfall? Because being hit by a waterfall...
え、聞いたぞ、滝に打たれてきたってのは。
Wait, I heard you went and got hit by a waterfall.
あれ、これってもしかして、ガチ滝？
Wait, is this actually... a real waterfall?!
いや、なんか、いわゆる体験のすごさに
Well, like, given the intensity of the experience...
プロライバーアイドルはみこ生のためには滝に打たれなきゃいけないってこと？
As a pro liver idol, does Miko have to get hit by a waterfall for her stream?
え、マジで？ まじか
Wait, seriously? For real?
なんか、みそぎと言えばみたいな感じっぽいですね。
It seems like a purification ritual kind of thing.
え、そうなんだ。
Oh, really?
やばいやばい、めちゃくちゃ寒かったよ。
Man, it was so freezing!
行こう行こう、じゃあ行きましょう。
Let's go, let's go, then let's go.
禊の一種 滝行に挑む
[Title: A form of purification: taking on waterfall training]
気温 6℃
Temperature: 6°C
おはようございます。すみません、半袖で
Good morning. Sorry, in short sleeves...
で、このままの画面で、あの、さっきの映像か、このままの画面ね、ここですごしてもらうのね。
So in this screen, um, the previous footage, in this same screen, you spend time right here.
だってさ、みこさんはしょうがないかなって思うけどさ、この人はさ、確かに！
I mean, Miko-san has no choice, but this guy is like... truly!
寒くないのかなと思うわけじゃないですか。でもほら、もうずっとね、あの、やって、やってる方だからさ。あ、もう慣れてるんだ。
You'd think he'd be cold, right? But see, he's been doing this for a long time. Ah, he's used to it.
あ、じゃあ、じゃあ、どうそどうそ。何が正解だったんだ。
Ah, then, go ahead, go ahead. What was the correct answer?
寒くないですか？ 蕎麦打ち前の準備だったので、蕎麦打ちしてるんですよね。
Aren't you cold? We were preparing to make soba beforehand, so I was making soba.
月待の滝 もみじ苑 店主 大関仁さん
[Title: Tsukimachi Waterfall Momiji-en, Owner Hitoshi Ozeki]
月待の滝を有名にするため昭和59年開店 滝行体験ができる
[Title: Opened in 1984 to make Tsukimachi Waterfall famous, waterfall training available]
そば食べたい
I want to eat soba.
早速、滝のもとへ
Now, towards the waterfall.
あの、有名な人も来るんですか？
Um, do famous people come here too?
トップアイドル来てます。櫻井翔さん来てますね。
Top idols come here. Sho Sakurai has been here.
月待の滝です。勢いがすごいですね。
This is Tsukimachi Waterfall. The force is amazing.
通常の水量です。
This is the normal water volume.
滝行のために、まずは承諾書に署名。住所とか書いてあるから、住所特定されてまう！
For waterfall training, first sign the consent form. Since my address is written here, my address will be doxxed!
えっと、11月26日土曜日...住所特定されてるから。
Uh, November 26th, Saturday... Since my address is doxxed.
あ、待って、天照大御神桜神社 350-3535
Ah wait, Amaterasu Omikami Sakura Shrine 350-3535
で、ここから年賀状をここに送ってくださいね... そりゃもしかしたらモザイクになるかもな。
And, please send New Year's cards here... That might become mosaic blur.
水温9.3℃ 禊開始
[Water temperature 9.3°C - Purification begins]
早朝なのでとっても寒いでし...
Since it's early morning, it's super cold...
なんでこんな事をしているのか、甚だ疑問に思っている次第。
I'm still questioning why I'm doing something like this.
うわぁ、ガチだ
Whoa, it's the real deal.
うわぁ〜！ ヤバいって！ 冷たっ！
Whoa~! This is crazy! So cold!
ヤバいヤバいヤバい...声、声、声！ 声遠い！ ピンマイクつけたらさ、水没してしまうからさ...声聞こえないじゃん
Yabai yabai yabai... Voice, voice, voice! Voice is far away! If I put on a lapel mic, it'll get waterlogged, so... can't hear my voice.
違うの、あのね、本当に滝の勢いがすごいの！ 滝でね、こっちの声がかき消されてるの。だから、マイクつけても水で全部やられちゃうから、こういうところからやらないといけないからさ。
No, you see, the force of the waterfall is really amazing! My voice was drowned out by the waterfall. So even if I put on a mic, water ruins everything, so we have to do it from a place like this.
ちょっとじゃあ音量上げてもらう。いやいや、この人のバランスが、人一人のバランスが大変なんじゃない。
Then let's have them turn up the volume. No no, the balance of this person alone must be tough.
リスナーさん！ まじで痛かったからね。
Listeners! It honestly hurt so much.
痛いんだよね、滝って、よし、確かに。いつもプロレスとかレースとか、喜んでてすみません！
It hurts, waterfalls, right, true. Always pro wrestling or races, sorry for being happy!
楽しんでてすみません。ごめんなさい。ボリューム上げて！
Sorry for enjoying it. I'm sorry. Turn up the volume!
どういうことそれ？ どういうこと？ 何を楽しんでって、ごめんなさい。いいじゃん。あの、やみこも必死に打たれてるから。
What does that mean? What do you mean? Enjoying what, sorry. It's fine. Well, Yamiko is desperately getting hit too.
何か言わなきゃ
We gotta say something.
みそぎよ！みそぎって何
A misogi! What even is a misogi?
みんなに対して、なんかあの、申し訳ないって気持ちは、なんかその日頃ね
Like, feeling sorry towards everyone, you know, day to day
みこぴーのことボコボコにしたいとか、
wanting to beat up 35P and stuff,
え？だから、ありがとう
Wait, so, thank you—
そこはなんか、なんだろう、「ありがとう」とかお伝え、伝えれないよね、あの、「ごめんなさ……」
you can't really say "thank you" or anything there, like, "Sorry..."
「ごめんなさい」って、気持ちが
The feeling of "I'm sorry"
出てくるんだ、ざけ
comes out, bull—
滝行やん、ざけんな！
That's waterfall training, bullshit!
すごい洗われた気持ち
I feel so cleansed.
奥に行くんだよね？
Going deeper, right?
もう手遅さじゃん
It's already too late!
痛い！痛いよ！
Ow! It hurts!
洗われる気がする
I feel like I'm being washed!
思うじゃないですか
You'd think that, right?
違うんだよ
That's not it!
次あっちだ！次あっちの方が、あの、勢い強いんで
Next is over there! The other side has more momentum, so—
よりみそぎをしようとしてるって
you're trying to misogi even harder—
そう、もう凄かった
Yeah, it was amazing.
これ、二箇所ともみそぎしたほうがいいの？
Wait, should I misogi in both places?
2022年……目の前が見えない
2022... I can't see in front of me.
寝坊をしてしまってごめんなさい！
I'm sorry for oversleeping!
ミーティングも何度か寝坊したことがあります、ごめんなさい！
I've overslept during meetings a few times, I'm sorry!
あと、なんだ？何もない。みこは何も悪くない！
And what else? Nothing. Miko did nothing wrong!
何も無い、いや、みそぎだから
Nothing... No, because it's a misogi.
もう終わりだ！
It's over!
禊終了！
Misogi complete!
どうでした？滝に打たれて
How was it? Being hit by the waterfall.
寒かったです、めっちゃ寒かった
It was cold, super cold.
いや、何々何々？今のサインちょっと戻して、今のもどれるかな？
Wait, what what what? Put that sign back, can you go back?
めっちゃ日光…嬉しい
So much sunlight... I'm so happy.
綺麗だったんだ、かわいい
It was so pretty, cute.
うれし……嬉しがりながら
Happily... while being happy.
もうしっかりとね、文字も書いて
Writing the letters firmly too,
もう早かったね、ここまでに来るのがびっくりしたよね
it was fast, I was surprised to get here.
誰なんだろうと思いながらね、ねえ？もしかしたらさ、飾ってあるかもしれないからさ
Wondering who it was, right? They might even display it.
ぜひ飾って下さいよ、ありがとうございます！
Please display it, thank you very much!
いかがでしたか？
How was it?
マジで寒かった、本当に風邪引くと思いました
It was seriously cold, I really thought I'd catch a cold.
禊は落ちましたか？
Was the impurity washed away?
あたたまりたいんで、温泉連れてってくれません？
I want to warm up, can you take us to a hot spring?
禊の感想聞きたいんですけど…
We'd like to hear your thoughts on the misogi...
温泉行きたい！
I want to go to a hot spring!
煩悩しかねえじゃねえか！
That's nothing but worldly desires!
あの、本当に濡れたまんまなの、こん時は。でもめちゃめちゃ寒くて
At that time, I was completely soaked. But it was super cold,
温泉に直行するよね
You'd go straight to a hot spring.
そのままだよね、なんか、ドライヤーで乾かすとかもなくて
Just like that, without even drying with a hair dryer.
ドライヤーあったんだけど、でも、もう気温も、そもそも寒かったからさ
There was a hair dryer, but the temperature was freezing to begin with.
11月ですからね、めちゃめちゃ寒かった
It was November, after all, super cold.
いや～あったまったな～、完全に貸切状態でしたよ
Man, I warmed up. It was completely private.
それはよかったです、改めて禊はいかがでしたか？
That's good. How was the misogi, now that you think about it?
すごいね、終わった後は
Amazing, after it was over,
なんか毒素が抜けたような感覚を覚えました
I felt like all the toxins had left my body.
今はなんかもう……無です。
Right now, it's like... nothing.
温泉のおかげも気がしますが…
That might be thanks to the hot spring though...
次は抱負を祈願しに行きましょうか
Next, let's go pray for our resolutions.
また何かするんですか？行けばわかります
We're doing something else again? You'll see when we get there.
いやでも、まあいっか。寝よ
Well, whatever. Time to sleep.
千葉県香取郡神崎町、大日山 神崎寺。ということで、なんか動きが、行いってみたいと思います！
Kanzaki-machi, Katori-gun, Chiba: Dainichiyama Kanzakiji. So, let's try performing it!
住職のもとへ、交通安全祈願所
To the head priest, traffic safety prayer ground
人生……人生ううんじじ？「人生是遍路」
Jinsei... Jinsei uunjiji? "Jinsei kore henro"
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
ダメだ、ダメだ、ダメだ、だって、あの、あの、仮にも神社の巫女さんですよね？
No way, no way, wait, isn't she supposed to be a shrine maiden?
一応ロケですよ？
This is supposed to be on location, you know?
待て待て待て待て、なんですが
Wait a second.
嘘だろ、おい。
No way.
いや、嘘だろ、逆に。
Wait, the other way around?
いや、おめえだろ！嘘だろ！
I'm telling you! No way!
はい、じゃあ次行きましょう。
Okay, let's go to the next part.
嘘つき！
No way.
人生は遍路。
Life is a wandering road.
これ、変形？これ変路だよ。
Wait, is this the wrong way?
これ変路だ、これ。変路ですね。
It's the wrong way.
こんにちは。
Good afternoon.
いや、本当にこれ変路なんだ。
Is this really the wrong way?
これ変路しかないだろ。
There's no other way.
こんにちは。
Hello.
本物の人だ。本物だ。副住職さんだ。
He's a real priest.
よろしくお願いします。
Hello.
何かオススメありますか？
Do you have any recommendations?
オススメ？
Recommendations?
おおい！
Oh!
ふざけてんのかと思った！
You thought it was a joke!
と勘違いして、住職さん、奥ゆかしい。
He completely misunderstood.
ご飯食べに来て「おすすめ」って！
We came here for lunch and asked for recommendations!
「お勧めがあるのかな？」みたいなね。
Thinking "Is there a recommendation?" like that.
まあ、とりあえずね。
Well, anyway.
何が新年でやりたいですか？
What do you want to do in the new year?
やっぱりアイドルを頑張っているので……
Well, since I'm working hard as an idol...
商売繁盛ですかね？
Prosperity in business, right?
もうちょっと可愛らしくヒット祈願の方がいいかも。
Maybe something cuter like a hit prayer.
努力する気ありますか？
Are you willing to put in the effort?
ねえ、ほら見て！今の文章見た？「努力する気ありますか？」
Look at that sentence, "Do you have the will to make an effort?"
これ凄くない？これ。
That's amazing!
やっぱりこれスクショ撮っておいて頂いて、これもう。
You should get that screenshotted.
ありがたいお言葉ですよ。
That's a very kind word.
ちょっとこれワイプ消して、みこち消して。
Wait, wipe this, Miko-chi.
やめろよ！
Stop it!
すげえレスポンス！やべえ、使えるねこれね、そう。
That's great, response! You can use this!
ハードル高いです、これ。
The hurdle is high, this.
お楽しみにしてください。
Please look forward to it.
ヒット祈願が流行語になりますね、みこちのね。
I think a hit prayer would be trendy for Miko-chi.
ヒット祈願がいいと思いますよ。
I think a hit prayer is a good idea.
はい……
Yes...
ちょっと辛いですよ？
It's tough?
辛いって例えばどんなことですか？
What do you mean by tough?
やってみれば分かります。
You'll understand if you try it.
辛い祈願とは…？
What is a tough prayer...?
住職に書いてもらったこちらを見せると、
Showing what the priest wrote down.
確認していきましょう。
Let's read them.
まず一つ目、ヒット祈願ですね。
First is the hit prayer.
そして…
And...
ああ、体が健康ね。
Ah, good health.
アイドルに不可欠ですよね。
That's essential for an idol, isn't it?
そしてもう一つは、
And the other one?
エリート祈願。
Elite prayer.
これは何ですか？エリート祈願というのは。
What is that? Elite prayer?
私、自称ではないんですけど、エリート巫女として活動しているので、
Well, I act as an elite shrine maiden...
2023年もエリートでいられますように。
So that I can remain elite in 2023 as well.
本当ですか？うんうん。
Is that so?
いや、でもみんなね、言ったらそうなるから、一応ね。
Everyone says that, but it's true!
いや、でも、自称だろうが、
Even though it's self-proclaimed!
自称だから言われてるの！
It's called that because it's self-proclaimed!
思ったのが、ヒット祈願にしようかなって思って、
I thought it would be nice to go with a hit prayer...
2023年もエリートでいられますようにと。
So that you can stay elite in 2023.
分かりました。
Understood.
じゃあこの3つ、
These three...
これから焚く護摩の中に、よくお願い事をしたのを、お不動さんに届けるために投げ込みます。
Throwing them into the goma fire to deliver the wishes to Acala.
うちの護摩はすごく激しいので、気をつけてください。
Our goma ritual is very intense, so please be careful.
分かりました。
Understood.
ということで、とっても辛い
And so, it's very tough.
これは護摩行に挑むんじゃないですか。
This is the goma ritual, isn't it?
護摩行とは燃え上がる炎の前で祈り続けることで願いを叶えるパワーを授かる修行とされており、
The goma ritual is said to grant wishes by continuing to pray in front of the burning flames.
炎の温度300℃に達することもある過酷な修行の1つ。
The flames can reach temperatures of 300°C, making it a harsh practice.
先ほど見てたのは護摩木と言われ、
What we saw earlier are called gomagi.
その炎の中に投げ込むことで不動明王に願いを届けてもらう。
Throwing them into the flames delivers your wishes to Acala.
でも、その前に…
But before that...
懺悔、懺悔、六根罪障、消滅煩悩、滅罪煩悩障…
Rokkon Shōjō, Zai Shōmetsu, Bonnō Metsujo...
こちらは礼拝と呼ばれ、自身の過ちや煩悩を「懺悔」していく修行。
This is called raihai, a practice to repent for one's mistakes and worldly desires.
煩悩の数と同じ108回一切休まず行う。
It is performed 108 times without rest, matching the number of worldly desires.
先ほどの懺悔で…みこは何も悪くないから、
Because Miko did nothing wrong in that repentance...
護摩行の前に…頑固な煩悩をさらに清める。
To further purify stubborn worldly desires before the goma ritual.
護摩行の前に…頑固な煩悩をさらに清める
Before the Goma ritual... purifying stubborn earthly desires even further.
出来るところまで頑張ってみましょう
Let's do our best as far as you can.
もし無理なときは「あー無理です」などで教えてください
If it gets too hard, please let us know by saying things like "Ah, I can't do it."
許されるんですか?
Is that allowed?
許すのは私じゃなくてお不動さまですね
It's not me who forgives you, it's Fudo Myo-o.
そうですよね~
That's right...
懺悔懺悔六根清浄
Repentance, repentance, purification of the six roots...
煩悩滅除五障消除
Eradication of earthly desires, elimination of obstructions.
懺悔懺悔六根清浄煩悩滅除五障消除
Repentance, repentance, purification of the six roots, eradication of earthly desires, elimination of the five obstructions.
みこさんの声はどこに行っちまったのかな?
I wonder where Miko-san's voice went?
そもそも声が出てないんですよ
She's not even making a sound to begin with.
みこさんいますか?
Miko-san, are you there?
います!
I'm here!
消えちゃったのかと思いました
I thought you had vanished.
懺悔懺悔六根清浄煩悩滅除五障消除
Repentance, repentance, purification of the six roots, eradication of earthly desires, elimination of the five obstructions.
あっくつした脱げた!
Ah, my sock came off!
礼拝を続けること…約10分
Continuing the prostrations... about 10 minutes
懺悔懺悔六根清浄みこ、みこ…
Repentance, repentance, purification of the six roots... Miko, Miko...
懺悔懺悔六根清浄煩悩滅除五障消除
Repentance, repentance, purification of the six roots, eradication of earthly desires, elimination of the five obstructions.
大丈夫ですか?
Are you okay?
あと75回頑張れますか?
Can you do 75 more times?
みこ35回じゃなかったっけ?
Wasn't Miko supposed to do 35?
がんばるがんばれないおい!
I can do it! I can't! Hey!
108回出来なくてすみませんでした
I'm sorry I couldn't do 108 times.
お不動さまに許しを乞う…
Begging Fudo Myo-o for forgiveness...
35回でってせめて！せめて35回までやってよと思ったんだよ！
You should've at least said 35 times! I thought we were doing 35!
35だよね？
It was 35, right?
そうだよ！
That's right!
35回って言ったじゃん！
You said 35!
お願いしますって言ってんだよ！
You were saying "Please!"
お不動さまに許しを乞う…
Begging Fudo Myo-o for forgiveness...
護摩行開始
Goma Ritual Begins
まずは炎が立ち昇るまで祈りを捧げ続けていくと
First, we continue offering prayers until the flames rise up.
目の前に300℃の火柱
A 300°C pillar of fire right before her eyes
みこさん今火が集っております。そこにあなたの祈りを…一本ずつ祈りを込めた護摩木を投げてください。
Miko-san, fire is gathering now. Into that, please throw the prayer sticks, each imbued with your prayer.
待って足つった！足つった！やばい！
Wait, my foot cramped! My foot cramped! Oh no!
みこがもたつくこと…約15分
Miko struggling for about 15 minutes
お願いします！約15分？燃えてる？
Please! About 15 minutes? It's burning?
違うのよ！何が？
That's not it! What is?
いやもうね、何が？
I mean, what is--?
ずっと正座してたわけよ。そしたらね、もともと太もそがパンパンなわけ。そしたらね、なんかだんだんね「あれ、足の感覚がないな」ってなって、こうぽこってやったら「あっ、つった！」ってなってさ！
I was sitting in seiza the whole time. Then my thighs were already super tight. Gradually I was like, "Huh, I can't feel my legs," and when I moved like this, I was like, "Ah, it cramped!"
えっ、つった！？つったってなったわけ？ / ええ、しょうがないのよ！15分間！
Eh, it cramped!? It went "it cramped"!? / Well, I couldn't help it! For 15 minutes!
もともと全然感覚なかったんだけど、急にやってたらさ！
My legs had zero feeling at all, and then all of a sudden while doing it!
いやもうさ、住職さんはさ、こいつ何しに来たんだろって / いや、お疲れ様だよ！しっかりやってたからさ、だけど！
I mean, the priest must have been like, "What did this person come here for?" / Hey, good job! You were doing it properly, though!
住職さんの怒りの炎を見てください
Please look at the priest's flame of anger
やっと来てくれた
You finally made it.
待ってくれた
You waited for us!
いやいや違うんだよ、ようやく護摩木を投げ入れ
No, no, that's not it. We finally threw in the gomagi sticks...
ここからは、住職とともに声に出してお経を唱えていく
From here on, we'll chant the sutras out loud together with the head priest.
一心祈願、心願成就
Single-minded prayer, fulfillment of wishes.
これ、すごい！すごい迫力なんだ...
This is amazing! Such incredible intensity...
その後も一心不乱に拝み続け…
After that, we kept praying with single-minded devotion...
およそ30分間に及ぶ護摩行を終え
Finishing about 30 minutes of the goma ritual,
いやぁ、ヤバかったね！
Man, that was intense!
ということでね、
So, um,
今日は、朝の4時から始まり
today, starting from 4 AM,
ロケに向かい
we headed to the location shoot,
滝に打たれ
got splashed under a waterfall,
そしてこちらに来たらね、燃えてもう本当に顔が焼けるかと思いましたけど
and then coming here, it was burning so much I thought my face was going to get scorched,
これが本当の…あっちゅあっちゅってことだよね
but this is what they really mean by "hot, hot," right?
みこちお疲れ様！
Miko-chi, great job!
黙れ！
Shut up!
邪魔え！
Back off!
はい、終わりということでね。お疲れ様でしたと。
Right, so that's a wrap. Good work to us.
いやぁ、もう本当に…求めました！凄かったでしょ、みこの
Man, truly... we asked for it! Wasn't Miko's amazing?
いや、どすかにね
I mean, honestly,
すごいよ、あの…ね、いい感じでございましたけどね
it's amazing, you know... it had such a good vibe, though.
凍え死にそうではありましたけどね
Though it felt like we were freezing to death!
そうだよね、そうですよね
That's right, yeah, exactly.
心神なメンタルをね
A purified mental state, you know...
本当に、なんか毒素抜けたみたいな感じだったよ
It really felt like all the toxins were purged.
あぁ、すっきりするの？
Ah, does it feel refreshing?
朝のさ、4時のさ、行ってさ、もう1日中のロケだったわけよ
Starting at 4 AM and shooting all day long, you know.
確かに、夜までだもんな
True, it was until night, after all.
そう、夜もだったからね。もう、うわぁみたいなさ
Yeah, it went into the night too. Like, "Whoa..."
凄げぇ体験したの。いやでも、いい良かったですね
We had an amazing experience. But hey, it was good, right?
あの、住職さん、金沢新庄さん？
That head priest, Kanazawa Shinsho-san?
はいはい。あの、とてつもなく厳しい方でしたね
Ah yes. He was an incredibly strict person, wasn't he?
すごい。
Totally.
いや、まだでも優しい方なんだよね。本当にね、すごいね、もう
Well, but he was a kind person still. Really, it's amazing, like...
撮影中などもしてて、そう、障害物を...おいって言ってたからね
While shooting and stuff... right, "Obstacles!" "Hey!" he was saying.
それをやったら、ちゃんと撮影のあれを考えて
If you do that, you gotta properly consider the camera angles and...
おい！おい！おい！ツッコミされる方だったんですね
Hey! Hey! Hey! He was someone who would deliver straight man tsukkomi lines!
本当に、役の方
Truly, the role...
いや、いい方だったなと。ありがとうございます。
Well, he was a great person. Thank you very much.
凍え死に旅でした。凍え死に旅でした。
It was a freezing-to-death journey. A freezing-to-death journey.
ということでね、あのVTRもこれで終わりということで、はーい。
And with that, the VTR comes to an end. Right.
じゃあ次は、みこが、まあ、なんだい？降臨と言いますか。
Well next, Miko will, um, what is it? Make a descent, as they say.
はい。やっぱり、みこらしくやっていこうかな？ということでね、まあお悩みをお抱えのフォロワーがいらっしゃるので
Yes. As expected, let's do it the Miko way, right? Since there are followers dealing with worries,
なるほどね、解決していこうかと思いまーす。
I see, we'll go ahead and resolve them.
たまにやってるあの企画ね。たまにやってる、たまに。
That project we occasionally do. We occasionally do it, occasionally.
本当に、全然人がこなかったやつね
Seriously, nobody showed up at all for that one.
じゃあ、この後ねどうなるのか楽しみにしていきましょう。
Well, let's look forward to seeing how things turn out after this.
はい、頑張ってください。頑張ってください。
Yes, do your best. Do your best.
はーい！
Byeee!
はい、ということでね！
Yes, and so!
いやぁ、すごかったな。滝に打たれ、ね、護摩行もして、足は切って、すごかった！ということで、今年もこの季節がやってまいりました！
Man, that was amazing. Getting hit by a waterfall, doing the goma ritual, cutting my legs, it was incredible! And so, this season has come around again this year!
年に一度の、みこ様のご降臨！
Once a year, the descent of Miko-sama!
みこさまが、お悩みを…お悩みを解決していきます！
Miko-sama will resolve your... resolve your worries!
ということで、年に一回しか見えない降臨しますよ。
So, appearing only once a year, I will make my descent!
それじゃ、みこさま、ご降臨――！
Now then, Miko-sama, descend—!
と いう…
Ta-da...
にゃんにゃんはろー！Eliteみこのさくらみこです。
Nya-nya hello! It's elite Miko, Sakura Miko.
ということでね、早速お悩みを抱えているフォロワーがいるということで
So, right away, we have followers who are burdened with worries,
じゃあそろそろ、来てるかな？
so let's see, are they here yet?
にゃんはろー！あ、どうもー！
Nya-hello! Ah, hello there!
うん に- ああ エリートの香りがする。
Hm, ni— Ah, it smells like an elite.
におい- におい- におい-
Smell— smell— smell—
みこちゃんだね、これね。
It's Miko-chan, isn't it.
う、すごい。なんの香りだこれは一体。
Whoa, amazing. What kind of scent is this anyway?
これはなんか焼かれたエリートの香り。
This is the scent of a roasted elite.
ご馬行スタートのエリートの香りだね、ねち。
It's the scent of an elite starting Gomagyou, nechi.
いや、足の爪すってるね、匂いがする。
Wait, it smells like rubbing toenails.
おっと？違う？はい？
Oops? Wrong? Huh?
とゆーことで自己紹介をお願いします！
And with that, please introduce yourself!
はい、ホロライブ5期生、オレンジ担当、桃鈴ねねです。
Yes, Hololive 5th Generation, Orange representative, Momosuzu Nene!
そして今日はつきぞいちゃん ホロライブ2期生大空スバルです、よろしくお願いします！
And today, accompanying her, Hololive 2nd Generation Oozora Subaru! Nice to meet you!
あーあけましておめでとうございます！
Ah, Happy New Year!
いや、とゆーことでね、ま、早速、どっちがお悩み抱えてるんですか？
And with that, let's get right to it—which of you has an issue?
ま、ちょっとね、あれ、なんか、そうだよね、言いにくいよね、ねねち。
Well, you know, um, that's right, it's hard to say, isn't it, Nenechi?
うん、ねえ、すごい、言いにくいねねち。
Yeah, hey, super hard to say, Nenechi.
ちょっとうちの子が、うちの子のお悩みを、ちょっと聞いてやってください。
Please listen to my child's issue for a bit.
では、聞いてやろう。言が痛いぞ？
Well then, I'll listen. Does your word hurt?
あ、待って、ちょっと待って、今、大本どっちがうことが起きて、混乱したねねちちょっと。
Ah, wait, wait a minute, the script got mixed up and I got confused, Nenechi.
え、では、ねねちの、あ、えと、あ、これね！はい、じゃあねねちのお悩みはこちら！
Umm, well then, Nenechi's, um, ah, this! Right, so Nenechi's issue is right here!
みこ先輩のことを「みこち～」と呼んでみたいけど勇気が出ないです。勇気と許可をくれよみこち～！！（！）
I want to call Miko-senpai "Miko-chi~", but I don't have the courage. Give me courage and permission, Miko-chi~!!
（「ち」の爆笑ねねちより）
(From "Chi"-laughing Nenechi)
なるほどなるほど。いや、これ、解決できそうですか、これは？
I see, I see. Now, can this be resolved?
いや、そもそもですね、あの、ねねちって、みこちって呼んでなかったんだっけ。
Well, first of all, um, Nenechi, didn't you call her Miko-chi?
そういえば呼んでなかった。え、なんて呼んでたの、ねねち？みこ先輩って。
Come to think of it, you didn't. Eh, what did you call her, Nenechi? Miko-senpai.
え、みこ先輩って呼んでて、え、呼ばなくていいよ！なんでだよ！
Eh, you called her Miko-senpai? Eh, you don't have to call her that! Why?!
みこちでいいでしょ！あ、今日ね、ご一緒のね、からするとね、大先輩なんだよ、ホロライブを創り上げた。
Miko-chi is fine! Ah, today, compared to us, she's a huge senior who built Hololive.
あ、なるほど。そうだよお。緊張しちゃうね。そうそうそう。
Ah, I see. That's right. It's nerve-wracking. Exactly.
分かりました。じゃあこちらのね、お悩みを解決していこうと思います。
Understood. Then I think we'll resolve this issue here.
え、これをこうしてと…、あ、ちょっと待ってね。えっと、えーと、これね、やっぱエリート、エリートと言える、あ、なんか来たぞ！
Um, doing this like this... Ah, wait a minute. Um, um, this, after all, an elite, you can say elite—ah, something's coming!
おお、来た！なにそれ？あなたの、お悩みを解決します！せいっ！
Oh, it's here! What is that? I will solve your issue! There!
ずばり！もう、みこちとねねちのユニットを組もう！
Boom! Already, let's form a unit with Miko-chi and Nenechi!
やったー！もうみこちなんでもビジネスする！そうだよね！
Yay! Miko-chi does business with everything! That's right!
え、じゃあ二人でユニット活動、始ま るってこと？ああ、そうなんだ！始まる始まる！まあユニット名は、なんだ、ダブちとかね、ダブち、ダブちいじゃん。ダブち、ダブち。
Eh, so unit activities between the two of us are starting? Ah, is that so! Starting, starting! Well, the unit name is, what, Dub-chi or something? Dub-chi, Dub-chi is good. Dub-chi, Dub-chi.
とかね。いやでも、今まで呼ばれてなかったってぐらいね、違和感なかったので、ぜひね、呼んでいただければと思います。
And stuff. Well, but since there hasn't been any weirdness about not being called that until now, I definitely want you to call me that.
あー！みこちー！あ、ねねちー！じゃあ今日からね、みこちとねねちでよろしいですかね？
Ah—! Miko-chi! Ah, Nenechi! So starting today, is Miko-chi and Nenechi alright?
あ、よろしくおお願いします。今年からね、よろしくおお願いします。
Ah, y-yes. Please treat us well starting this year.
ちょっと待て。これ、すばるいる？あれ？ちょっと待て。すばるいる？これ、すばるいる？
Hold on. Is Subaru here? Huh? Wait a minute. Is Subaru here? Is Subaru here?
すばるは、いや、今年もね、やっぱりね、うんうん。仲良くしてくださいね、ねねち。
Subaru, well, this year too, after all, yeah yeah. Get along well, Nenechi.
あ、ねねね？あ、ねねち？あ、ねねこもは？ねねこもじゃなくて、みこちが多すぎてわけわかんないことになってるって。
Ah, Nenene? Ah, Nenechi? Ah, what about Neneko? Not Neneko, Miko-chi is too much and it's getting confusing.
じゃあ、そろそろね、帰りましょうかね、時間もあれなんでね。帰りましょ、ね、二人でね、帰りましょう。じゃあ、お邪魔しましたー！
Well then, shall we head back soon, since it's getting late? Let's go home, hey, the two of us, let's head back. Well then, thanks for having us!
いや、なんか中身がかわいらしいお悩みだったの。ねえ、なんか、ちょっと、え？そうだったんだ。みたいな感じでしたね。ありがとうございます。
Man, the contents were such a cute worry. Hey, like, sort of, eh? Is that how it was? It felt like that. Thank you very much.
それでは、次の方、どうじょー！次もいるのかな？
Well then, next person, please! Is there someone next too?
あ、どうもどうも！あけましておめでとうございます！くでるくでる！えっと、え、自己紹介をお願いします！
Ah, hello, hello! Happy New Year! Kuderu kuderu! Um, um, please introduce yourself!
はい、あ、じゃあ、えっと私、今日は月添の知らんぬいフレアと！はい、ちょっと今回お悩み相談したいノエルです。よろしくお願いします！
Yes, ah, then, um, I, today accompanying me is Shiranui Flare! And, hi, I'm Noel who wants to consult about an issue this time. Nice to meet you!
あ、ノエル、フレア！あけましておめでとうございます！どうもどうも。あ、な、ちょっと、何気に団長のタッチ絵が新しいやつだちょっと。
Ah, Noel, Flare! Happy New Year! Hello, hello. Ah, wait, somehow the commander's art is a new one.
おめでとうございますね。
Congratulations.
今年もよろしくお願いしまーす！
Looking forward to working with you this year!
なんかすごい、ノエ、ノーキー…おなきしっぽいですね。
It's, um, very Noe... No-ki... NoeFure-like.
そう、ちょっとねこれ、拾い上げて決まったよ、お悩みを。
So, I've picked out the worries we're tackling!
じゃあ、そんなお悩み…二人のお悩みは何ですか？
So, what are those worries... what are their worries?
はい、ま、二人と言うかね、ちょっと、団長のお悩みかな？
Well, speaking of the two... it's more of the leader's worry, right?
個人的にちょっとこれ3年間思ってることなんですけど、いいですか？
Personally, I've been thinking about this for 3 years. Is that okay?
いいですよ。団長のお悩みは…
Sure. The leader's worry is...
ダダン！
Ta-da!
フレアがね、ちょっと、え、ASMRをしてくれなくて、はい。
Flare won't do ASMR for me... yeah.
ちょっとね…そろそろASMRをやしてほしいということでみこ様何卒よろしくお願いいたします。
So... I want her to do ASMR soon, so Miko-sama, please!
これまた難しい、確かに、なんかやらない人にさ、やらせるって難しいよね、みこっち。
That's also tough. True, getting someone who never does it to do it is hard, Miko-chi.
待って、一言すぎるの。え、君なんだよな？
Wait, that's way too brief. Wait, it's actually you, right?
え？あ、う、嘘ですね。
Oh, right, my bad.
まあ、みこならこれもう解決できる。だってさ、やってないもん、な。
Well, Miko can solve this. After all, she hasn't done it yet, right?
あれ、なんかちょっと、そうなんだって感じ。よくのひ人言ってるけど、できるかな？
It's like, is that really so? Noel keeps saying that, but can she do it?
で、君がイエスって言ったらいいんだよな？
And if you say yes, it's all good, right?
私の悩みをね、あ、みこ様が解決してくれる、最高！
My worry... Miko-sama is going to solve it, awesome!
では、そんなあなたに、え、授けましょう。
Then, let's bestow this upon you.
やはり、ノエルが無理やり、もう、ボイスに換気すればいいんじゃないですか？
Isn't it fine if Noel just forcibly locks her in the voice recording room?
ボイスに監禁して、こっち締めて、もう、ね、経費を置いて、ASMRしないと出れない部屋っていうことで感…
Lock her in the voice room, lock this side, leave the equipment, and make it a room she can't leave without doing ASMR.
監禁だ！監禁じゃんじゃん！いや、生きるよ。
Imprisonment! Imprison her right away! No, live!
この部屋にね、来年いるか？え、どうですか？それはちょっとあの、フレアどうですか？
Will you be in this room next year? Eh, how is that? Flare, what do you think?
イエスかノーかが聞けるっていうね。で、でもASMRはソロでは絶対やらないって話をしてて…
You can hear yes or no. But she says she'll never do ASMR solo...
あ、ノエルは別に、え、ノエルは別にやっていいよってずっと言ってたよ。
Ah, Noel kept saying she can do it whenever.
あの、ただ、あの、壊すから、壊してもいい機材でやってくれるって…
She said she'll do it with equipment she can break because she breaks things...
一体何をしようとしている？ちょっと恐ろ、だ、大丈夫？そんな、ね、あの、弱々じゃな…
What on earth is she trying to do? That's a bit scary... are you okay?
やったことあったんでしょ、そもそも？うん、やったことあるけど、ノエルはね、経費を1回やったから、ちょっと、ハード高いかな？
You've done it before, right? Yeah, I've done it, but Noel did it once, so the hurdle is high?
じゃあ、団長1割、フレア9割で今度コラボしようや。
Then let's collab next time with Leader taking 10% and Flare taking 90%.
おお、じゃ、それコラボ決まりましたね！じゃ、これ解決ということで。
Oh, then that collab is decided! Then consider this resolved.
いや、よかった。どうなることかと思ったわ。あ、ありがとうございます。
Oh, I'm glad. I wondered what would happen. Ah, thank you.
それじゃあね、今年もASMR期待しております！
Well then, we look forward to ASMR this year too!
楽しみだな。失礼します。ノエルね、ASMR楽しみだな。
I'm looking forward to it. Excuse me. Noel's ASMR, I'm looking forward to it.
で、フレアのね、これ解決できたのか？
And, was Flare's... was this resolved?
まあ、でもASMR、えっと、めちゃくちゃ匂いそうだけどね、フレアのASMR。すごい、楽しみだな。
Well, but Flare's ASMR... sounds like it'd smell amazing. I'm really looking forward to it.
ということで、じゃあね、最後の1組、どうぞ！
With that, now for the final pair, go ahead!
あけましておめでとうございます！
Happy New Year!
ボノ大作戦！ボノ大作戦…！
Bonno Operation! Bonno Operation...!
めちゃ振ってる！それ、ガラガラですか？赤ちゃんが持つやつ？ガラガラじゃねえよ！
You're shaking it so much! Is that a rattle? Is that for babies? That's not a rattle!
が、赤ちゃんがいるって聞いてきたんですけど。違いますけど！
I heard there was a baby here. That's wrong!
なんだ、ボノ大作戦って。あ、でもピンク組の仲間でしょ？
What is the Bonno Operation? Ah, but they're fellow pink hair members, right?
え、ピンク組の仲間だよ。え、ピンク組の仲間でしょ？
Eh, fellow pink hair group members. Right, fellow pink hair group members?
ただ、ちょっと今までの一組、2組というか2組は、結構片方のお悩みって感じだったんですけど…
However, the previous pairs, or rather pairs 1 and 2, were mostly worries from just one person...
船長とこよりは、もう完全に悩みが一致したので、二人で一つの願いを出してきたと。
Captain and Koyori's worries completely matched, so they submitted a single wish together.
願い叶えてまいりましたよ。よーし、よーしと。
We've granted your wish. There, there.
お、じゃあいきますか。お、裏…裏です、それ裏やなそれ。
Oh, shall we go? Oh, the back... it's the back, that's the back.
おっぱいが大きくなりますように。
May our breasts grow bigger.
おっぱいが、あ、大きく！なりますように。せーの、ぼいーん！こよりよ！
May our breasts... ah, grow bigger! Ready, boing! Koyori!
投げた！ちょっと、そんなさ、おっぱいちゃんなんか投げんな！
She threw it! Hey, don't just throw the boob tablet like that!
いやいやいや、もう、なるほどですね。まあ、そういうのもありますよね。いや、もう、感じになっちまうよ、これ。
No, no, no, well, I see. Well, things like that happen too. Man, this has turned into this kind of vibe.
でも隠れてるから、なんか、みこちも、なんかあの、衣装いつもね、桜の花びらで乳首隠してますよね。
But since it's hidden, Miko-chi also always hides her nipples with cherry blossoms in her outfit.
いや、やめろや！乳首隠してないから、あれ！そう言うふうに見えるだろうが！
Hey, stop it! I'm not hiding my nipples with that! That's just how it looks!
おっぱい、ま、大きいんですけど、
My boobs are, well, pretty big, but
ま、みこち自分でおっぱい大きいと思います？
do you think your own boobs are big, Miko-chi?
まあ、まあ、それなりにあるんじゃないかななんて思ってます、えっと。
Well, I think they're somewhat decent, you know, um...
えっ？
Huh?
思うじゃないですか。でもこの程度のおっぱい意味ないんですよ。
You'd think so, right? But this level of boobs is meaningless.
えと、はい。
Uh, yeah.
小さいまである、もはや。
They're practically small at this point.
小さいな？
Small?
いや、ホロライブ基準にするとね、
Well, if we go by Hololive standards,
そう、さっきのね、ASMRの、ちょっと、ね？
yeah, that ASMR from earlier, you know?
そうなんですよ。ちらの程度のおっぱいじゃあおらわれてしまう、これ悔しいすよね。
That's right. With this level of boobs, you just get teased. It's frustrating, right?
ね、こんなに大きいのにな？
Right, even though they're this big!
そう、まあ、確かに確かにね。
Yeah, well, true, true.
これを、ちょっと、あおられない手は、やっぱ頭、ピンク髪この3人組、全員ちょっと爆乳になりませんか？
To avoid getting teased about this... hey, the three of us with pink hair, shouldn't we all become busty?
一緒に、そうそう、一緒にになりましょうよ。
Together—yeah, yeah, let's do it together!
いや、みこは別にいいんですけど、じゃあ、
I mean, I'm fine as I am, but then...
でもね、あなたたちにぴったりの、解決策思いつきましたよ！
But you know, I came up with the perfect solution for you guys!
おお！
Oh!
いや、これしか無い！やったあ！
This is the only way! Yay!
お前らにはこれしかない！それでは授けましょう。
This is all you've got! Then I shall bestow it upon you.
ズバリ！お互いの乳をもみあって、
Exactly! Knead each other's boobs,
大きくし合えばいいんだあ！
and make each other bigger!
ごろごろごろごろ...え？
Roll roll roll... Huh?
あれ？ピンク組、
Huh? The Pink Group...
え、まじで、まじでがっかりした。
Seriously, seriously disappointed.
いや、なんか、今すぐぽいんって大きくなるとか、そういう魔法とかかけてくれると思ってたよね、普通。
I mean, I thought you'd cast some magic to make them pop and get big right away, normally.
です、魔法的な何かを...
Right, some kind of magic...
そんなことできるわけないよ、みこは。
There's no way I can do that, Miko.
あれ？何しに来たんだろね、なんかね。
Huh? What did they even come here for?
なんこ、ここ。
Like, seriously.
やめたら？やめたら、ここ。もう自分で揉むわ！
Why don't you quit? Quit this. I'll just knead them myself!
いや、人にも、揉んだほうがいいんじゃないんですか？
No, isn't it better to have someone else knead them?
え、よね。ね、ほら、じゃあちょっとみこのおっぱい二人で揉み...飲みもうか。ね？
Right? Hey, look, then let's have the two of us knead—drink Miko's boobs? Right?
でも揉む時にはなんかトライアングルの形になってね、三人で揉み、揉みトライアングルで。
But when we knead, it'll form a triangle shape, the three of us kneading in a triangle.
あ、確かに。三人で、揉み揉みトライアングルで！
Ah, true. The three of us in a kneading triangle!
その、裁かれる、恐ろしい曲で...はああ、ありがたうございました！今年もよろしくお願いします！
By that terrifying song where we get judged... Haaa, thank you very much! Looking forward to this year as well!
お願いします！お願いしまーす！
Please! Please!
はあ、恐ろしいな。
Haah, how terrifying.
なんかいつの間にか、なんかもう新しい頭がピンクなやつもすごい、すごくこと言い出して。
Somehow, before I knew it, even the new one with pink hair started saying crazy things.
もうホロライブは、やっぱりエロライブってことなんですかねと、いうことで。
Like, Hololive really is an Ero-live after all, huh? So,
まあ、今のちょっとなかった、なかったことにしよう。
well, let's pretend that just now didn't happen.
まあ、なかったことにして。
Yeah, let's pretend it never happened, and
まあ、これでね、解決できましたかね？
well, did we manage to resolve this?
まあ、去年のね、もし神社も、まあ、これで大丈夫でしょう。
Well, last year's Moshiki Shrine, too, should be fine with this.
いやあ、ちょっとね、昔の姿に戻っても、
Man, even when I went back to my old look,
どうにもならん、どうにもならんこともある。ということでね、
some things just can't be helped. So,
悩みも解決を、できていないけど、できた！ということでね。
well, my worries weren't resolved, but they were! So!
いやあ、エリートパワーがみなぎる！ついに新お正月衣装！
Man, elite power is surging! Finally, the new New Year outfit!
ま、新と言っても初めてこのみこ服しかなかった。
Well, even though it's "new", I only ever had this Miko outfit before.
みこ、お正月衣装！いきますよー！
Miko, New Year outfit! Here we go!
お正月はどんな衣装なんでしょうか！わくわくわくわく！いくぞ！
What kind of outfit is the New Year's one?! I'm so excited! Let's go!
おっ、あれ？また光ってる！また光っているー！
Oh, wait? It's glowing again! It's glowing again!
こころぴょんぴょん待ち？
Waiting with a fluttering heart?
考えるふりして
Putting on a thinking face,
もうちょっと近づいちゃえ
I'll get just a little closer.
簡単には教えないっ
I won't tell you easily!
こんなに好きなことは内緒なの
Keeping how much I like you a secret—
ふわふわどきどき内緒ですよ
It's fluffy, pounding, and a secret, you know.
はじめのかんじんは
The beginning feeling is
つうんどうんどぅあ
tsun-tsun-do-ah!
ふわふわどきどき内緒だって
Fluffy, pounding, and a secret,
いたずら笑顔でぴょんぴょん
with a mischievous smile, pyon-pyon!
扉開けたとたん見知らぬ世界へと
The moment I open the door to an unfamiliar world—
(そんなの ないよ)
(There's no such thing)
ありえない
That's impossible,
それがありえるかも ミルク色の異次元
or maybe it's possible? A milk-colored dimension!
(コーヒーカップ) 覗い たらり
(Coffee cup) Peeking in,
私が私を見つめてました
I found myself staring back at me.
なんで？なんで？ふたりいる？
Why? Why? Are there two of us?
(うそっ！)
(No way!)
困りますね (きって) おんなじ趣味 (だから)
It's troublesome (surely) sharing tastes (so)
誰を (見つめるの？君でしょ！)
Who are you (staring at? It's you!)
君だけ見てるよ
I'm only looking at you.
(これは夢 カップの夢 飲みほして おしまい？)
(Is this a dream? A cup's dream, shall we drink it down?)
いつもぴょんぴょん可能！
Pyon-pyon is always possible!
楽しさ求めて もうちょっとはじけちゃえ
Seeking fun, let's burst out just a little more
(ぴょんぴょん と)
(pyon-pyon-to)
一緒なら素敵だーい！
Together is wonderful!
君に言わせたいから
Because I want you to say it,
(言いなさいいっ)
(say it!)
こころぴょんぴょん待ち？
Waiting with a fluttering heart?
考えるふりして
Putting on a thinking face,
もうちょっと近づいちゃえ
I'll get just a little closer.
簡単には教えないっ
I won't tell you easily!
こんなに好きなことは...
Keeping how much I like you...
こころ ぴょんぴょん 待ち？
Waiting for my heart to go pyon-pyon?
考える ふりをして もうちょっと 近づいちゃえ
Pretending to think, I'll get just a little closer.
簡単には 教えないっ
I won't tell you so easily!
こんなに 好きなことは 内緒なの
It's a secret how much I love you.
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒ですよ
It's a fluffy, pounding secret, you know.
はじめ がんじゅん つう だ つう だ
It's getting serious right from the start!
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒だって
I said it's a fluffy, pounding secret—
いたずら 笑顔で ぴょんぴょん
with a mischievous smile, pyon-pyon!
日常 の 中 に も
Even in our daily lives,
不思議 の 交差点
there's a mysterious intersection.
ありえない 角度 に 切り分けた ケーキ が
A cake sliced at an impossible angle—
呼ん じゃっ た よ
(As expected of a rabbit) called out to me!
私 も 私 と 驚き まし た
I was just as surprised as anyone.
なんで? なんで? 喋る うさぎ? 困り ます ね
Why? Why? A talking rabbit? (Seriously?!) I'm in trouble.
おんなじ 趣味 だから 誰 を 見つめる の? 君 でしょ!
Sharing the same hobby, who am I looking at? It's you!
君 だけ 見 てるよ
I only have eyes for you.
いつも ぴょんぴょん 可能! 楽し さ 求めて もう ちょっと はじけちゃえ
Always pyon-pyon possible! Seeking fun, let's burst out even more.
一緒 なら 素敵 だーい! 君 に 言わ せ たい から
Together, we're unbeatable! I want to make you say it.
こころ ぴょんぴょん 待ち? 考える ふりをして もうちょっと 近づいちゃえ
Waiting for my heart to go pyon-pyon? Pretending to think, I'll get just a little closer.
簡単 に は 教えないっ
I won't tell you so easily!
こんなに 好き な こと は 内緒な の
It's a secret how much I love you.
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒 です よ
It's a fluffy, pounding secret, you know.
はじめ がんじゅん つう だ つう だ
It's getting serious right from the start!
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒 だって
I said it's a fluffy, pounding secret—
いたずら 笑顔 で ぴょんぴょん
with a mischievous smile, pyon-pyon!
胸 が ランラン 歌う! スキップ シナガラ ハニカン で 誘って よ
My heart sings run-run! Skipping along, acting shy, invite me out.
一緒 なら 無敵 だーい! 本音 隠せ なく なる
Together, we're unbeatable! I can't hide my true feelings.
明日 ランラン 希望? 今 すぐ が いい な ハニカン で 誘って よ
Tomorrow run-run hope? Right now would be nice, acting shy, invite me out.
一瞬 だけ 耳もと ホント は 好き な ん だ と ササヤク
For just a second, whispering into your ear that I really do love you.
いつも ぴょんぴょん 可能! 楽し さ 求めて もう ちょっと はじけちゃえ
Always pyon-pyon possible! Seeking fun, let's burst out even more.
一緒 なら 素敵 だーい! 君 に 言わ せ たい から
Together, we're unbeatable! I want to make you say it.
こころ ぴょんぴょん 待ち? 考える ふりをして もうちょっと 近づいちゃえ
Waiting for my heart to go pyon-pyon? Pretending to think, I'll get just a little closer.
簡単 に は 教えないっ こんなに 好き な こと は 内緒 な の
I won't tell you so easily! It's a secret how much I love you.
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒 です よ いたずら 笑顔 で ぴょんぴょん
It's a fluffy, pounding secret, you know, with a mischievous smile, pyon-pyon!
かじかむような 季節 なのに
Even in this numbing, freezing season,
キミ は なぜ か 少し 嬉し そう で
you somehow look a little happy,
戸惑っ てる 僕 を 連れ出し
leading me out as I hesitate,
くるり 回っ て
spinning around
歌っ て くれ た ん だ
and singing for me.
「ねえ 笑わ ず に」って 「聞いて ね」って キミ は 言う
"Hey, don't laugh," "Listen to this," you say,
窓辺 に はしる 流氷 みたい な キミ と の 運命
running by the window, like drifting ice, our destiny together.
見つけ た 一輪 の さくら
A single cherry blossom we found,
「どう?」って 照れ ながら
asking "How is it?" while looking shy,
振り向い た その 笑顔 も
that smile when you turned around—
ずっと 見守っ て い たい な って
I want to keep watching over it forever,
そう 思っ た ん だ
that's what I thought.
まだ 冷え込む 季節 だ から
Since it's still a chilly season,
桜 の 木 も 眠っ て いる のに
even though the cherry trees are still sleeping,
「待ち遠しい な」って 笑う キミ は 僕 に とって は
you smiling and saying "I can't wait" means to me—
枯れ ない 桜 だ
an unfading cherry blossom.
ずっと 変わら ず に ここ に い てって
Staying right here without ever changing,
僕 は 言う 「どこ に も 行か ない よ」って
I say, "I'm not going anywhere."
優しく 笑っ て た そんな やりとり も
You smiled so gently, and even those little exchanges—
きっと 小さな 幸せ で
are surely a small happiness.
ずっとそれが続きますように
May it continue forever.
そう思ったんだ
That's what I thought.
春が来てすぐ夏が来て
Spring comes, summer comes right after,
秋が来てすぐ冬が来て
Autumn comes, winter comes right after.
何度だって君と過ごしていたいな
I want to spend time with you no matter how many times.
また僕たちの何気ない今日が過ぎる
Another ordinary day of ours passes.
だけどキミが楽しそうにしてる
But just by you looking like you're having fun,
それだけで
just by that alone...
ボクの中からはあたたかくなる気がするんだ
My heart feels warm inside.
だからせーので約束しよう
So let's make a promise on the count of three:
ずっと一緒だよ
"We'll be together forever."
はい！ということで、新衣装は、和風メイド服でーす！お正月衣装、やっともらえてありがとうございます！
Yeah! So, the new outfit is a Japanese-style maid uniform! Thank you so much for finally getting a New Year's outfit!
わあ可愛いんでしょ！めちゃくちゃ可愛い！フリフリがね、おムネになっております！
Wow, isn't it cute?! Super cute! The ruffles are all over the chest!
次で、なんと、最後の曲です！
Next is, surprisingly, the final song!
わあ！次の曲は、なんと！もう新年にぴったりの新曲でーす！やったー！わーい！
Yay! The next song is, believe it or not, a brand new song perfect for the New Year! Yay! Woohoo!
ということで、2023年もさくらみこ、よろしくねー！
So, please keep supporting Sakura Miko in 2023 too!
放て この想いを赤裸々に
Release these feelings starkly and plainly,
響け 乙女の唄
Resound, maiden's song!
前向け ぐんぐん しゅっぱつ進行
Look ahead, full speed, departure, advance!
立ち止まる予定あるわけない
There's no plan to stop anywhere!
笑顔にさせちゃう かみさま信仰
Faith in the god who makes you smile!
それつまり どこの どちらサマ？
So, exactly who might you be?
さぁ 始めようか 空を染め上げて
Now, shall we begin and dye the sky?
ほらあっちもこっちもそっちもどっちもにっちもさっちも華やかに変えていこうよ！
Look, here, there, everywhere, whichever way, let's make it gorgeous!
さくらひらり 時は来たり 天つ乙女のように
Cherry blossoms fluttering, the time has come, surely like a heavenly maiden,
きっと！きらりきらり輝くから 信じてついてきてね！
Sparkling, sparkling, because I'll shine, believe in me and follow along!
さくらひらり 夢を見たり どんな困難だって
Cherry blossoms fluttering, dreaming dreams, no matter what difficulties arise,
きっと！キミと二人乗り越えるよ うまずたゆまず さぁ すすめ！
surely I'll overcome them together with you! Without pausing, without slacking, now forward!
艶やか SUN SUN 昇る太陽 春の光射すハレの日に
Glossy SUN SUN, the rising sun, on a clear day bathed in spring light,
気ままなフリして 心に抱いた キミに届けたいこの想い
acting as you please, holding in your heart this feeling I want to reach you!
さぁ 悩みこくる 人は聞きなさい そういっぱいしっぱいどんまい
Now, those who are worrying, listen up! Lots of failures, don't mind that,
それよりいっぱいぜったいしあわせを知れば大吉！
and more importantly, if you know happiness, it's a great fortune!
さくらひらり 時は来たり 天つ乙女の気持ち
Cherry blossoms fluttering, the time has come, the feelings of a heavenly maiden,
ずっと胸に胸に持ち続けて 願いを叶えてくよ！
always holding them in my heart, continuing to hold them, I'll make my wishes come true!
さくらひらり 夢を見たり 焦がれた景色がある
Cherry blossoms fluttering, dreaming dreams, there is a scenery I yearned for,
ずっとキミとならね 掴めるから 退かずおそれず いざ すすめ！
always because if I'm with you, I can grasp it! Without backing down, without fear, now forward!
かじかむ
Numb with cold...
かじかむ冬に たったひとり
In the numbing winter, all alone,
枝の先 膨らんでいた つぼみ
the buds were swelling at the tips of branches.
春の風を 待ってたんだよ
They were waiting for the spring breeze.
それは キミという風
That is the wind called you,
背中を押す まぶしいパワー
a dazzling power that pushes my back.
さくらひらり 時は来たり 天つ乙女のように
Sakura fluttering, the time has come, like a heavenly maiden!
きっと！きらり きらり 輝くから 信じてついてきてね！
Surely, it shines so bright, so believe and follow me!
さくらひらり 夢を見たり どんな困難だって きっと！
Sakura fluttering, seeing dreams, no matter the difficulty, surely!
キミと二人 乗り越えるよ
With you, we will overcome it together.
うまずたゆまず さあ ススメ！
Unflaggingly, come on, advance!
はーい、ということでみなさん、今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Hi there, everyone, thank you so much for today!
えー、細かいところはね、ま、あのこのあとメンバー限定で、メン限はこのあと21時、え、21時15分からとなっておりますので、ぜひ来てくだサーイ！
As for the details, the members-only stream starts at 9:15 PM, so please come!
そして、え、先ほど聞いていただいた新曲、
And the new song you just heard,
『乙女のススメ♡！』こちら、えー本日の24時、各音楽サイトでリリースされますので、ぜひたくさん聞いてください！
"Otome no Susume♡!" will be released tonight at midnight on music sites, so please listen!
さらに！重大発表ですね。
And furthermore, a major announcement!
もう一つのなんと！重大な告知は、こちらです！どんっ！
Another surprise! The major announcement is right here! Ta-da!
鳴門鯛焼き本舗さんとさくらみこコラボ決定します！2月の下旬よりコラボ予定となっております。
Naruto Taiyaki Hompo and Sakura Miko collaboration! Scheduled from late February.
コラボ限定デザインのたい焼きBOXが登場！そして描き下ろしはなもり先生にお願いしました！
Collab-exclusive taiyaki boxes by Namori-sensei!
お正月衣装のね、が、そのね、たい焼きのね、こう、こういうことですよね。もうたい焼きの、もう看板娘みたいな感じのわけですよ。はい、もうたい焼きがね、ありますと。
New Year outfit version eating taiyaki like this, acting as the poster girl!
そして、え、お正月衣装の描き下ろしの人のもあります！
And there are also items with the new New Year illustrations!
はい、こちらですね。コラボ期間中は一部店舗にみこのパネルなども飾られ、もう本当にね、いろいろありますので、コラボグッズとかも、もう色々、なんかもうすごいから、みんなね、あの続報をお楽しみにと いうことで、
During the collab, Miko panels will be displayed at some stores, so look forward to updates!
え、今年もね、どうぞよろしくお願いします！今年も頑張っていくぞ！
Thank you for your continued support this year too! Let's do our best!
えいとパワー！がんばるぞー！ありがとうございましたー！
Ei-to Power! Let's do our best! Thank you very much!
ありがとうねみんな！またねー！このあとの指折りタイガもね、みんな頑張ってねー！ばいばーい！
Thank you everyone! See you later! Everyone do your best! Bye-bye!